Demitrios E. Pournarakis

Information Technology Scientist, PhD Athens University of Economics & Business

Elpidos 13, 4th Floor, 10434, Athens, Greece Tel: +30 210 8203822 Email: pournadi@aueb.gr

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 28/05/1983 Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Greek / American

Military Service: 2005 – 2006, Hellenic Air force

SPECIALIZATION

I am an Information Technology Scientist with strong interest in Digital Marketing. I apply computational tools to data oriented problems that focus, but are not limited to, analyzing consumer insights as well as conversion optimization of marketing campaigns. Experienced Technical Project Manager with strong skills in defining and documenting architecture, capturing and documenting requirements, preparing estimates and defining technical solutions to proposals.

EDUCATION

2013 - 2017	PhD in Digital Marketing
-------------	--------------------------

Athens University of Economics & Business

Supervised by: George M. Giaglis

Thesis Title: BRAND EQUITY ASSESSMENT - A Computational Model for Mining

Consumer Perceptions in Social Media

2010 – 2012 MBA international

Athens University of Economics & Business

2006 – 2007 MSc in Information Systems

City University London

2001 – 2006 BSc in Management of Information Systems

Athens University of Economics & Business

2004 Erasmus, Corporate Finance

Brunel University

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2018 – present Adjunct Lecturer, Athens University of Economics & Business

Network Science, iMBA

2005 – 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, Athens University of Economics & Business

- Introduction to Computer Science (*Undergraduate*)
- Introduction to Social Network Analysis (*Undergraduate*)
- Information Systems I (*Undergraduate*)
- Information Systems II (*Undergraduate*)
- Management of Information Systems (MBA Telecoms & MBA International)
- Social Network Analysis (MSc in Decision Sciences MBA International MSc in Business Analytics)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2017

2008 – 2012	IT Consultant , IBM Drove and coordinated the offshore global delivery team, located in India, in designing, building and delivering large scale CRM projects.
2012 - 2013	Pre-Sales Consultant , IBM Responsible for configuration and setup of IBM Big Data Analytics offerings. In charge of IBM Watson Social Media Analytics tool.

Technical Project Manager, Athens University of Economics & Business Led the architecture, design and implementation of the new website of Athens University Economics and Business. Interaction and consultation with all key stakeholders.

2013 – Present

Co-founder / Business Development Manager, Nimbata
Founding member, from conception to implementation of the core Call Conversion
Tracking offering. Responsible for frontend design (HTML, CSS, PHP) and Business
Development. Company currently serves more than 30 customers worldwide.

2013 – Present Researcher, Athens University of Economics & Business

Member of IST Lab and Sociomine research team, involved in research in Online Social

Networks through use of Data Science (SQL, R, Python, Gephi, etc.) and Machine

Learning Algorithms

VOLUNTEER WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 – Present **Mentor**, Google Startup Weekend

Part of mentor network for Google's startup weekend network in Volos, Greece

2015 **Mentor**. Ionian University

Part of the mentor team for the Adriatinn Innovation weekend

REVIEWER FOR SCIENTIFIC JOURNALS

Decision Support Systems, Information Systems and e-Business Management

LANGUAGES

English: Native, Cambridge Proficiency Certificate

Greek: Native French: DELF B2

COMPUTING SKILLS

Data Analysis: SQL, R, Excel

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
General Programming: PHP, Python, C (Basic Skills)
Server Administration: UNIX. Windows Server

Enterprise Software: Certified Oracle Siebel 8 Consultant

Visualization Tools: Gephi, Inkscape, GIMP CMS Tools: WordPress, Drupal

SCHOLARSHIPS - CERTIFICATIONS

1998 National Bank of Greece

1st prize in essay writing on the subject of "Savings and its benefits"

2005 IKY

Scholarship for outstanding performance during the Erasmus Program

2009 Oracle

Certification in Oracle Siebel 8 suite, awarded from Oracle with distinction

2009 IBM

Certification in IT Governance

2010 IBM

Scholarship to attend AUEB's international MBA

2013 General Secretariat of Research and Technology - Greece

Three year scholarship to finance PhD in Management Science & Technology at Athens

University of Economics & Business

2015 National Bank of Greece

4th prize with Nimbata startup in the 2015 "Innovation & Technology" Competition

MAJOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

2013 - 2016 Sociomine Research Platform

Academic research platform set in Ubuntu server for Data mining and Data Analysis through Machine Learning Technologies. Ubuntu Administration, Python, R, SQL

2013 – Present Nimbata

Website: http://www.nimbata.com

Frontend development with HTML, CSS, Inkscape, JavaScript

2011 - 2012 IBM Social Media Analytics (Watson Analytics)

SQL, Regex, Data Analysis

Development, Configuration and Analysis in COBRA, applied in data through various

verticals (banking, telco, retail, insurance, etc.)

2008 - 2011 Oracle Siebel Upgrade

Oracle Siebel, SQL, Windows Server Administration

Team member of large transformational project in one of the leading

telecommunication providers in Greece

INVITED TALKS

2015	"Disrupting the marketing scene" , University of Thessaly, Change Management Open Seminars
2015	"Using time-series and sentiment analysis to detect the determinants of Bitcoin prices", Athens University of Economics & Business, 12^{th} FSDET
2014	"Integrating call tracking in digital marketing campaigns", ${\tt EEDE,10^{th}}$ internet $\&$ e-business innovation forum
2013	"IBM Social Media Landscape", ALBA Business School, Executive MBA

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Kopsidas, A; Pournarakis D; (2018) "A computational approach to analyzing the political scene of Greece", 15th annual DMST Conference, 3 May, Athens, Greece
- 2. Pournarakis, D; Sotiropoulos, D; Giaglis, G. (2017) "A computational model for mining consumer perceptions in social media", *Decision Support Systems*, Volume 93, January 2017, Pages 98-110 (ABS: 3 Impact Factor: 3.565 5-year impact factor: 4.574 CiteScore: 4.65)
- 3. Sotiropoulos, D; Pournarakis, D; Giaglis, G, (2017) "SVM-Based Sentiment Classification: A Comparative Study against State-of-the-Art Classifiers", International Journal of Computational Intelligence Studies, Volume 6, Issue 1
- 4. Pournarakis, D. (2017) "Brand equity assessment: a computational model for mining consumer perceptions in social media" (Doctoral dissertation, Athens University of Economics & Business, Department of Management Science & Technology).
- 5. Sotiropoulos, D; Pournarakis, D; Giaglis, G, (2016) "A Genetic Algorithm Approach for Topic Clustering: A Centroid-Based Encoding Scheme", Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Information Intelligence, Systems and Applications, 13-15 July 2016, Halkidiki, Greece
- 6. Georgoula, I., Pournarakis, D., Bilanakos, C., Sotiropoulos, D., & Giaglis, G. M. (2015) "Using time-series and sentiment analysis to detect the determinants of bitcoin prices", *Proceedings of the 9th Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems*, 3 5 Oct 2015, Samos Greece.
- 7. Sotiropoulos, D; Pournarakis, D; Giaglis, G, (2015) "Semantically aware time evolution tracking of communities in co-authorship networks." *Proceedings of the 19th Panhellenic Conference on Informatics*, 1-3 October 2015, Athens, Greece
- 8. Sotiropoulos, D; Pournarakis, D; Giaglis, G, (2015) "Tracking the Evolution of Communities in Co-Authorship Networks: A Semantically Aware Approach" *Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Information Intelligence, Systems and Applications*, 6-8 July 2015, Corfu, Greece
- 9. Bouros, N; Sotiropoulos, D; Pournarakis, D; Giaglis, G, (2014) "Social Network Analysis Within The ICMB Community: Co-Authorship Networks" *Proceedings of the ICMB 2014: 13th International Conference on Mobile Business*, 2014, 4-5 June 2014, London, UK
- 10. Pournarakis, D., Kounavis, C., Sotiropoulos, D., Giaglis, G. (2013) "AT&T VS VERIZON: Mining Twitter for customer satisfaction towards North American Mobile Operators." *Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on Mobile Business (ICMB 2013)*, June 10-13, 2013, Berlin, Germany